JAMIE: Jamie here — and there's a surprise deal making waves.
ALEX: Alex on markets — the S and P five hundred is up zero point zero seven percent, while the Nasdaq is up zero point four seven percent, and the Dow is down zero point one nine percent.
MAYA: Maya from tech — that deal is a big move.
ALEX: The biggest gainer today is a company up three point two seven percent, and the biggest loser is a company down two point five two percent.
JAMIE: Right, and what about the macro side of things — any notable moves?
ALEX: The ten-year Treasury yield is down zero point four one percent, and the dollar index is down zero point one percent.
MAYA: And in the world of AI, there are early signs of AI not just coding its own products but building itself — that's a big deal.
JAMIE: Hold on, that's not right — isn't that company warning about AI risks?
MAYA: Yeah, that's the same company — it's like they're trying to have it both ways. Oh, come on — it's not all hype, there are some real breakthroughs happening.
JAMIE: What about the gas prices story — any updates on that?
ALEX: Yeah, gas prices won't be returning to pre-war levels anytime soon, according to a news source — that's a big hit for consumers.
↳ source: https://www.axios.com/2026/05/07/gas-prices-iran-war-peace-deal
MAYA: And a company just posted stronger-than-expected quarterly profit, thanks to a war sending fossil fuel prices soaring.
JAMIE: Wait, what — doesn't that mean they're profiting from the war?
MAYA: Yeah, that's one way to look at it — but they're also cutting back on share buybacks.
ALEX: Because nothing says "good corporate citizen" like profiting from war and cutting back on shareholder returns.
MAYA: Hey, at least they're being consistent — and a stock just surged thirty percent post-earnings.
JAMIE: This show is for entertainment and education only — nothing here is investment advice.