JAMIE: Cisco just posted record quarterly revenue while firing nearly four thousand people—apparently profitability and mass layoffs are now the same line item.
ALEX: S&P 500 up zero point four three percent to seven thousand four hundred seventy-six, Nasdaq up zero point three nine percent at twenty-six thousand five hundred five. Broad market shuffle — small caps actually down a tenth of a percent, which tells you everything about where the money's flowing. Spoiler: it's not flowing to Russell two thousand land. Cisco. Up thirteen point one seven percent on the news that they're cutting nearly four thousand people while posting record revenue. This is the Crocs IPO of corporate governance — a thing that should not work is somehow the hottest item in the room. Broadcom also up three point three eight percent, Accenture up almost three percent. Infrastructure and networking plays are having a moment because the AI-spending narrative finally pivoted from "buy Nvidia at any price" to "actually, someone has to build the pipes."
MAYA: Wait, Nvidia only up two point five seven percent? That's like — that's your mega-cap darling barely moving while the plumbing companies are ripping. Is the hype finally hitting a wall?
ALEX: Google down one point one seven percent. Amazon down zero point six four percent. Lilly down zero point seven one percent. When your trillion-dollar companies start leaking, yeah, the narrative shifts. Broadcom and Cisco aren't replacing Nvidia — they're just the thing people remember exists when they realize you can't actually deploy an AI cluster without fiber optic cable and switching gear.
JAMIE: So Cisco chose violence today by being honest about needing fewer people. And the market rewarded it like it invented the internet again.
MAYA: Okay so a Russian government hacking group tried to compromise Signal, the encrypted messaging app, by targeting a security researcher who works at Citizen Lab. And the researcher basically caught them mid-attack and reverse-engineered their entire spyware campaign. This is not a hypothetical anymore. This is Russia actively trying to crack the one app that's supposed to be uncrackable.
JAMIE: Wait, they targeted him because he investigates spyware, or just random targeting?
MAYA: Because he investigates spyware. He's literally the guy who exposes state-sponsored hacking operations. So Russia looked at this and went, "You know what would really help us? If we could hack the guy whose job it is to expose us hacking people." It's like breaking into a locksmith's house to steal his lock picks.
ALEX: And they chose Signal specifically because Signal's entire business model is "we don't know what you're saying, neither does anyone else." If you're the Russian government and you want to surveil dissidents, activists, or your own people calling you out, Signal is the wall you keep hitting. So yes, of course they're trying to crack it.
JAMIE: So Signal is basically the one app that actually works, which means every authoritarian government on Earth is now treating it like a personal challenge.
MAYA: Right, and here's the thing—the researcher found that the F S B was using zero-day exploits, which means vulnerabilities that nobody knew about yet, to try to get into Signal accounts. The attack was sophisticated enough that it would've worked on most people. But they caught it, documented it, and now Signal and Citizen Lab have gone public with the whole thing.
ALEX: Which means the F S B now knows that particular attack vector is burned. So they'll just pivot to the next zero-day. This is security Whack-A-Mole, except the mole is a nuclear-armed state with unlimited resources and the hammer is your encrypted messaging app.
JAMIE: Does Signal actually have the technical ability to stop this kind of attack, or is it just a matter of time before they find another way in?
MAYA: Signal's architecture is actually solid—end-to-end encryption means even if the F S B gets into the app on your phone, the messages themselves are still locked. But the attack here was targeting the phone itself, not Signal's encryption. It's like, Signal built an impenetrable safe, but Russia just kicked down your front door instead.
ALEX: Which brings us to the real problem: there are only so many front doors before you run out of house. Every zero-day Russia burns on Signal is one less zero-day they can use on literally anything else. So from a game-theory perspective, the fact that they're willing to spend this kind of capability on one researcher means Signal is actually winning. They're making it expensive to target.
JAMIE: So the moral of the story is Signal is so secure that the only way to crack it is to not crack Signal at all—just break into your phone some other way.
MAYA: Exactly. Signal is the Crocs IPO of encryption—a thing that should not be this effective is somehow the most secure thing in the room, and now every government on Earth is mad about it.
ALEX: UK economy grew in the fourth quarter, beating expectations. Inflation actually came down without the recession everyone was predicting, which means the rate hikes actually worked instead of just destroying growth like the script said they would.
JAMIE: So the UK did the thing where they fought inflation without nuking the economy?
ALEX: Apparently. The consensus was "raise rates, kill growth, pick one." The UK raised rates and kept growth. It's the one place where inflation theater produced an actual plot twist instead of just a recession with good intentions.
MAYA: That's wild because every other central bank was like, "Pain now, stability later," and the UK was like, "What if we just... didn't?"
JAMIE: Kevin Warsh just got confirmed as the next Federal Reserve chair while Trump is in China trying to make trade deals, which means you've got two completely different economic policies running in parallel—one person trying to stabilize the currency and one person trying to negotiate tariffs like they're real estate deals.
↳ source: https://www.federalreserve.gov/newsevents/pressreleases/other20260514a.htm
ALEX: Warsh is going to be fighting Trump's instinct to devalue the dollar for trade advantage. The Senate confirmed him, so now you've got a Fed chair whose entire job is to say no to the President's economic theater.
MAYA: So Trump's in Beijing going "let's make a deal" and Warsh is sitting there watching the dollar move and thinking, "This is going to be a long four years."
JAMIE: On the tape tomorrow, we've got earnings rolling in and some macro data that could actually move things. Alex, what's the big release?
ALEX: We don't have a major C P I or jobs number until next week, but Warsh's first policy meeting as Fed chair is effectively priced in already—the market's decided he's going to hold rates steady and sound concerned about inflation while Trump's tariff negotiations create actual inflation. It's theater where everyone knows the ending.
MAYA: But earnings-wise, tomorrow's May fourteenth and we've got Aveanna Healthcare, which is a home healthcare company that's been getting crushed because labor costs are up, reimbursement rates are stagnant, and every nursing home operator is basically choosing between margins and staff. They report tomorrow and the question is whether they finally admit the business model is broken or just keep saying it's "normalizing."
JAMIE: So Aveanna's basically the canary in the coal mine for whether healthcare staffing actually works at scale?
MAYA: Exactly. Plus you've got B K Technologies on the same day—they make radio communications gear for first responders, which sounds boring until you realize that every police department and fire service in America is supposed to upgrade to digital systems and they keep pushing the deadline back because the budget never materializes. B K Tech's earnings will tell you whether that upgrade cycle is actually happening or if it's just regulatory theater.
↳ source: https://www.theverge.com/tech/928905/vibe-code-personal-software-revolution
ALEX: So tomorrow we find out if healthcare labor is sustainable and whether the government actually follows through on spending it promised. Two things that determine whether half the market's earnings assumptions hold up. Cisco reported record revenue while laying off nearly four thousand people last month—basically proving that in modern corporate math, headcount is now a profit center. They're not cutting staff because business is bad; they're cutting staff because Wall Street discovered that firing people is cheaper than innovation and way more efficient than actually competing.
MAYA: So they're not restructuring, they're just admitting that the org chart was a spreadsheet and some rows were taking up valuable margin space.
JAMIE: This show is for entertainment and education only — nothing here is investment advice.