JAMIE: Jamie here — and it looks like Spirit Airlines is shutting down after failing to reach a bailout deal, because who needs discount travel anyway?
ALEX: Alex on equities — the market is seeing some gains today, with the S and P five hundred up zero point two nine percent, and the Nasdaq up zero point eight nine percent, but let's not get too excited, it's not like the fundamentals have changed or anything.
CAM: Cam on macro — rates are down, with the ten year Treasury yield at four point three eight percent, and the dollar is up slightly, but it's all just a big shrug from me.
MAYA: Maya from tech — have you seen the news about Anthropic's new Claude four point seven release? The benchmark numbers are absurd, with software engineering tasks at ninety-four percent accuracy, but I'm still waiting for the bear case to show up.
KAI: Kai with a question — does anyone actually understand what's going on with the market right now, or are we all just making it up as we go along?
ALEX: Well, Kai, it's not like we have a crystal ball or anything, but it seems like the market is just reacting to whatever headline comes out next.
JAMIE: Yeah, and it's not like we're just a bunch of monkeys throwing darts at a board or anything.
MAYA: Oh, but speaking of tech, have you seen the news about Shokz's new OpenRun Pro two headphones? They're on sale for forty dollars off, and they're supposed to be amazing.
RIO: Rio checking in — I saw a story about a couple who lost one hundred eighty-five thousand dollars in retirement savings because no advisor was actually managing their account, and I just can't even.
TESS: Tess at retail — it looks like used EV sales are surging, and the ownership costs are actually pretty comparable to gas-powered cars, but don't tell anyone I said that.
DEV: Dev on crypto — Bitcoin is up zero point zero four percent, but who's really paying attention to that right now?
KAI: Kai with the weird thing — did you hear about the guy who won the Powerball and his first call was to his ex-wife to gloat? And now she's suing him for the lottery ticket because he bought it on a joint credit card.
JAMIE: Of course she is — because that's just how these things always go.
CAM: Cam on macro — it's just another day, another dollar, another chance for the market to do something crazy.
MAYA: Maya from tech — I'm just waiting for the other shoe to drop, or in this case, the other algorithm to kick in.
ALEX: Oh, don't worry, Maya, I'm sure it'll all make sense in the end — or not.
JAMIE: Alright, alright, let's wrap it up — Tess, what's the last word?
TESS: Just that I'm still trying to figure out what's going on with the market, but hey, at least it's entertaining.
KAI: And I'm just here for the free snacks.
JAMIE: This show is for entertainment and education only — nothing here is investment advice.