JAMIE: Jamie here — and Tesla just hit a 'symbolic' self-driving milestone, whatever that means, with Elon Musk saying it's a major step towards safe unsupervised self-driving.
ALEX: Alex on markets — and the S&P five hundred is down zero point four one percent, not exactly a thrilling day, with the Dow Jones down one point one three percent.
MAYA: Maya from tech — and Palantir is having a great day, posting its fastest revenue growth ever, which is pretty impressive, and they're calling out 'AI slop', whatever that means.
JAMIE: Right, exactly, because who doesn't love a good AI controversy?
ALEX: Well, the Nasdaq is only down zero point one nine percent, so I guess that's a win.
MAYA: And Oracle is up four point nine two percent, which is a big move, after they announced their quarterly earnings.
ALEX: Oh, just the usual — beats on earnings and revenue, nothing too exciting.
MAYA: And Micron has risen up the ranks of the top U.S companies, which is a big deal, and they weren't even in the top one hundred last year.
JAMIE: That's a huge jump — what's driving that?
ALEX: Well, their fortunes have changed dramatically, mostly due to their recent investments and partnerships.
MAYA: And I heard Spirit Airlines just shut down, which is kind of sad, but also not surprising, given their financial struggles.
JAMIE: Yeah, I guess you could say they just ran out of runway.
ALEX: Oh, great, a aviation pun.
MAYA: And GameStop just made a surprise bid for eBay, which is a huge deal, and could potentially change the retail landscape.
JAMIE: That's a big move — what's behind it?
ALEX: Well, GameStop is trying to expand its business, but it's not clear how they plan to pay for it.
MAYA: And the creator of Roomba is back with a new robot companion, which is kind of cool, but also a bit weird.
JAMIE: Yeah, because what everyone needs is a robot friend.
ALEX: Anyway, the ten-year Treasury yield is up one point five five percent, which is a big move.
MAYA: And the dollar index is up zero point two seven percent, which is not too exciting, but still a move.
JAMIE: Right, exactly — it's all about the small moves today.
MAYA: And I heard the US government is warning of a severe CopyFail bug affecting major versions of Linux, which is kind of scary.
JAMIE: Yeah, because who doesn't love a good cyber threat?
ALEX: Well, at least it's not a boring day in tech.
MAYA: And the Met Gala just happened, and the fashion is insane, as always.
JAMIE: Yeah, because who doesn't love a good fashion disaster?
ALEX: Anyway, that's all for today — it's been a wild ride.
MAYA: And don't forget to check out the Pulitzer Prize winners, which were just announced.
JAMIE: Yeah, because who doesn't love a good book?
ALEX: Well, that's all for now — thanks for tuning in.
MAYA: And we'll be back tomorrow, with more news and more jokes.
JAMIE: This show is for entertainment and education only — nothing here is investment advice.