JAMIE: A M D just went full throttle — up eleven point four four percent — while the chip sector chose violence today across the board.
ALEX: Alex on markets. S and P five hundred up zero point eight four percent, Nasdaq up one point seven one — tech is carrying this thing. A M D at four fifty-five, A V G O at four thirty, C S C O up four point seven nine. Meanwhile the Dow basically flatlined at plus zero point zero two percent, which is the market equivalent of showing up to work and standing very still.
MAYA: Treasury yield down sixty-four basis points, dollar index fell forty-two basis points — that's real movement. Gold up zero point four four percent.
JAMIE: So what's driving the chip rally? Is there actual news or are we just riding the A I wave again?
ALEX: There's no tape catalyst I can see. C S C O earnings are coming Wednesday, but A M D moved before any new announcement. This is pure sector momentum — semiconductor strength on nothing but vibes.
MAYA: Vibes is the Crocs I P O of market explanations, by the way.
JAMIE: That's going on the board. What about the losers?
ALEX: M C D down two point eight percent, L I L Y down two point seven two, C R M down two point four three. Financial sector got dinged — B A C down two point seven three. The Fed rate-cut delay that Goldman just forecasted is probably the pressure.
↳ source: https://seekingalpha.com/news/4590241-goldman-forecast-fed-rate-cuts-delayed?utm_source=feed_news_all&utm_medium=referral&feed_item_type=news
MAYA: Wait, Goldman said rate cuts are delayed?
ALEX: Goldman pushed their cut forecast back on inflation. No specific new data yet — C P I drops Wednesday. But the market's pricing in fewer cuts than it was last week.
↳ source: https://seekingalpha.com/news/4590241-goldman-forecast-fed-rate-cuts-delayed?utm_source=feed_news_all&utm_medium=referral&feed_item_type=news
JAMIE: So we're tech-heavy, financials are sad, and nobody knows what inflation actually is. Got it.
MAYA: Apollo's C E O just said there's a thirty-five percent chance of a major market shock from A I-driven upheaval. Thirty-five percent! That's oddly specific. That's the confidence level of a weather forecast for Tuesday.
ALEX: Nothing says "I have no idea what's coming" like a specific percentage.
MAYA: He's warning. But also — if your entire job is to manage money through chaos, saying "chaos is coming" is job security. It's not a prediction, it's a business model.
JAMIE: Okay, different angle — CrowdStrike expanded their cybersecurity coalition. What's the play there?
MAYA: C R W D is just adding partners to their ecosystem. It's not a revenue driver, it's a P R move dressed up as strategy. "We have friends" is not earnings.
ALEX: The market has spoken. C R W D didn't move on the news, which means the market agrees with you.
JAMIE: N V D A partnered with Corning on optical connectivity. That one actually matters?
MAYA: That's real — supply chain muscle. But this isn't today's move. The chip sector rally is just momentum.
ALEX: T S L A up four point zero two percent, U N H up two point seven seven. Consumer healthcare and electric vehicles are both happy. Nothing coherent about the day — it's a grab bag.
JAMIE: So we've got tech ripping, financials bleeding, rates falling, and the dollar getting softer. That's actually a pretty clean picture.
MAYA: It's the "Fed might pause cuts" picture. Inflation isn't dead yet, but people are betting it rolls over before Wednesday's C P I. If they're wrong, Tuesday gets ugly.
ALEX: V I X up zero point six four to seventeen point one nine. Not panicky. Just watching.
MAYA: It means he's seeing A I concentration risk everywhere. The Mag Seven are carrying the market, and if A I spending doesn't pay off, valuations unwind hard. That's not crazy — that's real. But saying "thirty-five percent" is insane. He could've said "it's possible" and been equally honest. The number is just marketing for "pay us to hedge."
JAMIE: Is he wrong though?
ALEX: Not wrong. Overspecific. The market is priced for A I to print money forever. If it doesn't, we have a problem. But that's been true for eighteen months.
MAYA: Right, and the market keeps going up anyway. So either he's right and we're ignoring the risk, or he's wrong and the risk is priced in. Thirty-five percent doesn't help us figure out which.
JAMIE: Okay, moving on. Goldman's Fed forecast just got pushed back on inflation. What's the C P I risk for Wednesday?
↳ source: https://seekingalpha.com/news/4590241-goldman-forecast-fed-rate-cuts-delayed?utm_source=feed_news_all&utm_medium=referral&feed_item_type=news
ALEX: If inflation is hotter than expected, the market gets a reality check. If it's cooler, we rally into the weekend. Basically, we're guessing.
MAYA: But the bond market is already pricing in a pause. Treasury yields are down sixty-four basis points. That's a bet that the Fed doesn't cut as much as people thought. If C P I confirms that, we're fine. If C P I is hot, we gap down.
JAMIE: So Wednesday is actually dangerous.
ALEX: Wednesday is dangerous. But that's why the Dow is flat today — nobody's taking risk before the number.
MAYA: Meanwhile, the Humanities scored a victory against Trump's cost-cutting efforts.
↳ source: https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/2026/05/neh-grants-doge-trump-ruling/687126/?utm_source=feed
ALEX: That's not a market story, that's a culture story.
MAYA: But it's funny. They tried to automate something with A I, a judge said no, and now they have to actually do the work. It's the most bureaucratic possible outcome.
JAMIE: Okay, quick hits. Lebanon says an Israeli strike killed seven people including a child. The ceasefire is holding in name only.
↳ source: https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cn4pjegk358o?at_medium=RSS&at_campaign=rss
ALEX: That's a geopolitical risk, not a market move.
MAYA: The real story is that the Middle East is still on fire, and H M S Dragon is heading to the Strait of Hormuz. If that escalates, oil spikes. If it doesn't, we're fine.
JAMIE: How much does oil have to move to matter?
ALEX: Honestly? Not much. Energy sector is down today. If Brent hits one hundred ten, equities get nervous.
MAYA: That's not odd, that's just bureaucracy.
JAMIE: So A M D is still up eleven point four four percent on pure momentum, Goldman pushed back rate cuts, and Wednesday's C P I is the real event. If inflation is hotter than expected, we're gonna look back at today as the calm before the tape got messy.
ALEX: Thirty-five percent chance of a major shock, remember? Apollo's C E O called it.
JAMIE: This show is for entertainment and education only — nothing here is investment advice.