JAMIE: The thirty-year Treasury just hit five point one eight percent—highest since two thousand seven. The bond market is choosing violence today.
↳ source: https://www.cnbc.com/2026/05/19/treasurys-yields-inflation-traders-fed-interest-rates.html
ALEX: The S&P dropped zero point eight five percent to seven thousand three hundred thirty-nine. Nasdaq took it harder at minus one point two seven percent. Russell 2000 got absolutely demolished—down one point six four percent. And the V I X spiked one point eight, which tracks because the bond market is still choosing violence. Equities are red, rates are up, and somewhere a Fed official is probably saying this is "transitory."
JAMIE: "Transitory" is the Crocs IPO of economic forecasting—everyone knows it's wrong, but they keep saying it anyway. So what's actually moving money today? Are we in a "rates are real" panic or a "tech earnings are cooked" situation?
ALEX: It's both, which is why you're seeing this weird bifurcation. Pharma is having a party—Eli Lilly up three point one seven percent, Abbvie up two point seven seven, Merck up one point nine. Meanwhile, semiconductor stocks are in fetal position. A M D down three point four five percent, Broadcom down two point eight four. Amazon and Tesla both down over three percent. Turns out when your entire business model requires cheap capital, expensive capital is bad for you.
MAYA: Wait, so we're having a "old economy wins" day? Like, actual profit-generating pharma companies are beating the "we'll disrupt healthcare through vibes" crowd?
ALEX: The real story is crude tanking. That's deflationary pressure, which should theoretically be good for equities, except rates are spiking anyway because the market has decided the Fed's not cutting as much as it thought. The dollar's up. Everything's confused.
JAMIE: So the bond market chose violence, the Fed's credibility is on life support, and pharma is the only thing that makes sense because—what, people are always going to get sick?
ALEX: It's the only business model that doesn't require the Treasury to be rational. Everyone's just sitting in cash waiting for the next press conference. This stock market has commitment issues.
JAMIE: So the Musk versus Altman trial ended on procedural grounds, which means two of the richest men on Earth spent months fighting over OpenAI's soul and then just... stopped. Like they got tired. And here's what nobody examined: neither side could actually explain what they're building or why it's worth what it's worth.
↳ source: https://www.axios.com/2026/05/19/musk-altman-openai-trial
ALEX: The trial collapsed because Musk's lawyers couldn't prove OpenAI breached its nonprofit charter, which is hilarious because the real question never got asked in discovery. The judge just said no standing, case dismissed, everyone go home.
MAYA: Wait, but that's the thing—like, Musk wanted to force OpenAI to open-source everything, which sounds noble until you realize he's literally trying to tank his competitor while he's got his own AI startup burning cash. And Altman's over there defending a closed model that nobody can actually audit. So the entire trial was just two billionaires arguing about who gets to be opaque more legally.
↳ source: https://www.axios.com/2026/05/19/musk-altman-openai-trial
JAMIE: But the real scandal is that the court never had to answer the actual question: what is OpenAI's product? Is it a research organization? A for-profit company? A nonprofit that somehow justified its valuation? Because if you can't explain that in court under oath, how are you explaining it to investors?
ALEX: You're not. You're just telling them the growth curve is vertical and the moat is "we got there first." The trial would've exposed that if it had actually happened.
MAYA: The entire AI industry just took an L because the settlement proved that when the stakes get real—like, actual courtroom real—everybody lawyered up and ran. Not because they won, but because they all realized the same thing: if a judge starts asking "What is this actually worth and why?" the whole thing collapses like a house of cards built on venture capital and hype.
JAMIE: So Musk loses, Altman loses, OpenAI loses, and the only winner is the judge who got to dismiss the case without ever having to understand what artificial general intelligence is. Which, to be fair, puts him ahead of everyone else in the room.
↳ source: https://www.axios.com/2026/05/19/musk-altman-openai-trial
ALEX: C I S A—the federal agency literally tasked with protecting critical infrastructure—left plaintext passwords and cloud authentication keys on the open web in a public GitHub repository. A journalist found them. This is the cybersecurity equivalent of a bank leaving the vault combo on a Post-it note taped to the front door.
↳ source: https://techcrunch.com/2026/05/19/us-cyber-agency-cisa-exposed-reams-of-passwords-and-cloud-keys-to-the-open-web/
JAMIE: So the agency that tells every other agency "secure your passwords" couldn't secure its own passwords. How many passwords are we talking?
ALEX: Reams. Spreadsheets full. The kind of exposure that makes you wonder if C I S A's internal Slack is just screenshots of login credentials with "don't share this" written on top.
MAYA: Wait, so the people who are supposed to be stopping hackers from getting into the power grid just handed them a cheat sheet? Like, did anyone even check if the repo was public before uploading infrastructure data?
ALEX: Apparently not. And the really fun part is this has been up there long enough that you have to assume foreign intelligence services already grabbed copies. This stock has commitment issues with its own job description.
MAYA: Congress is scrambling to regulate prediction markets right now—you know, the platforms where people literally bet on election outcomes and policy decisions. They're freaking out because of insider trading allegations and want new guardrails up immediately.
↳ source: https://www.axios.com/2026/05/19/prediction-market-kalshi-polymarket-bill-congress
JAMIE: But prediction markets are the only price discovery mechanism in finance that's still honest. Why would you regulate the one thing that's actually working?
MAYA: Because regulators always show up three years after the party's already happening. Crypto got regulated after the bubble, meme stocks got regulated after the volatility, and now prediction markets are getting regulated right as they're becoming the only market that reflects actual information instead of Fed press conferences and CEO vibes.
ALEX: The irony is Congress is trying to ban insider trading on prediction markets while simultaneously allowing members of Congress to trade on non-public information about their own legislation. It's theater. They're doing regulatory theater.
MAYA: The FDA under the M A H A administration is loosening restrictions on unauthorized vapes and scrapping a proposed ban on minors using tanning beds. We're speedrunning the entire nineteen-eighties health crisis playbook in fast-forward.
JAMIE: So the agency that's supposed to protect public health just decided tanning beds for teenagers are fine? What's the actual regulatory justification here?
MAYA: There isn't one. They're just removing guardrails because the administration doesn't believe in guardrails. Vapes, tanning beds—next week they'll probably legalize asbestos if someone frames it as a "innovation opportunity."
ALEX: The FDA went from "we're banning flavored vapes to protect kids" to "actually, let's let kids have unlimited access to nicotine delivery devices." That's not regulation. That's surrender with a press release. Oil just hit its highest price since the Iran war started. Deutsche Bank put out a note saying markets are completely sleeping on the actual shock risk here.
JAMIE: So we've got geopolitical escalation, oil spiking, and the market's just... not pricing it in?
ALEX: The market's pretending it's transitory. Deutsche Bank's saying if the situation deteriorates further, you're looking at significant shock scenarios. Nobody's hedged for it. This stock has commitment issues with reality.
MAYA: Wait, so oil's at the highest level since the war started, rates are up, equities are confused, and the entire market structure is just hoping nothing else breaks? That's not a market. That's a Jenga tower with the bottom blocks already missing.
JAMIE: On the tape tomorrow—Home Depot reports earnings on May nineteenth, and we're going to find out if Americans are still willing to spend money on home improvement or if we've collectively decided that living in a house held together by duct tape and prayers is the new normal.
ALEX: Home Depot's carrying the entire consumer discretionary thesis right now. If their same-store sales are flat or negative, that's not just a Home Depot problem—that's a signal that the middle class has officially stopped renovating and started rationing. They're the canary in the coal mine, except the canary is a major retailer and the coal mine is the American consumer.
MAYA: And then you've got Driven Brands also reporting on the nineteenth—they own car maintenance chains. If Home Depot's weak, Driven Brands is going to be catastrophic because people defer car maintenance before they defer home repairs. You stop fixing the kitchen, but you still need your brakes to work. So if both of these report soft, we're looking at genuine demand destruction, not just inventory normalization.
JAMIE: So May nineteenth is basically the "are consumers actually broke" test, and the market's just going to sit here and pretend it doesn't matter until the numbers hit?
MAYA: The best part is C I S A's entire job is to tell private companies they're doing security wrong, and they're out here proving they can't even do the bare minimum. They don't get to lecture anyone about password protocols anymore—they forfeited that credential the second someone found their stuff in the digital equivalent of a dumpster behind a 7-Eleven.
JAMIE: This show is for entertainment and education only — nothing here is investment advice.