JAMIE: A M D's stock surged today, what's behind that surge, Alex?
ALEX: Alex on equities — A M D's earnings report showed data center growth pushing revenue and guidance past estimates, which is a big deal for investors.
MAYA: Maya from tech — and it's not just A M D, the whole AI sector is buzzing.
JAMIE: So it's all about the AI boom, but what about the broader market, Alex?
ALEX: The S and P five hundred is up zero point eight nine percent, the Dow is up zero point nine seven percent, and the Nasdaq is up one point one five percent, so it's a pretty positive day overall.
MAYA: And Disney's stock surged eight percent on its earnings beat, with streaming profits booming — that's a big win for the company.
↳ source: https://www.investors.com/news/disney-earnings-q2-2026-dis-stock-streaming-disney-parks-experiences-dow-jones-warner-bros-paramount-wbd/?src=A00220&yptr=yahoo
JAMIE: What about the losers — who's taking a hit today?
ALEX: Oh, just the usual suspects — oil prices are down.
MAYA: And Cruise passengers are stuck on a ship with a hantavirus outbreak — that's a real nightmare scenario.
↳ source: https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/clype7ededzo?at_medium=RSS&at_campaign=rss
JAMIE: So, what's the story with the US-Iran deal hopes — is that what's driving the market today?
ALEX: Reports have raised hopes of an agreement between the US and Iran, which is causing oil prices to drop — but we'll see how that plays out.
MAYA: And in other news, a Finnish AI lab is making waves in the AI lab scene.
JAMIE: Wait, what's the Finnish AI lab — tell us more.
MAYA: It's a lab founded by the former CEO of A M D's AI division — they're working on some pretty cutting-edge tech.
ALEX: Because what the world really needs is more AI startups with vague promises of "revolutionary" tech.
MAYA: And Uber's stock is surging on its delivery business strength — that's a big win for the company.
↳ source: https://www.marketwatch.com/story/ubers-stock-surges-as-deliveries-business-shows-surprising-strength-50be87e5?mod=mw_rss_topstories
JAMIE: What about the bigger picture — what's the macro outlook looking like?
ALEX: The ten-year Treasury yield is down one point one eight percent, and the dollar index is down zero point five one percent — so it's a bit of a mixed bag.
MAYA: And Bitcoin is up zero point five percent — that's a small but significant move for the crypto market.
JAMIE: So it's a bit of a wait-and-see game for now.
MAYA: And in a weird story, a man in Ukraine used robots and drones to capture territory — that's a whole new level of warfare.
JAMIE: What's the implications of that — is this the future of war?
MAYA: It's definitely a sign of things to come — unmanned warfare is becoming more and more prevalent.
JAMIE: That's a bit unsettling — the rise of the machines, and all that.
MAYA: Don't worry, Jamie, the robots won't take over... yet.
JAMIE: This show is for entertainment and education only — nothing here is investment advice.