JAMIE: Jamie here — and PayPal just beat earnings and revenue expectations, but their shares are down anyway, what's going on?
↳ source: https://www.investors.com/news/technology/paypal-stock-pypl-paypal-earnings-news-q12026/?src=A00220&yptr=yahoo
ALEX: Alex on markets — the issue is their June-quarter guidance came up short, overshadowing the positive signs from the latest period.
JAMIE: Wait, what? They beat expectations but still got punished?
ALEX: Yeah, the market's all about future growth, and PayPal's guidance didn't quite live up to that.
MAYA: Maya from tech — and this is a perfect example of how Wall Street can be super harsh, even when a company does everything right.
JAMIE: Right, exactly. It's like they're saying, "Great job, but not great enough."
ALEX: The market's also worried about the new CEO and how they'll handle the company's growth going forward.
MAYA: And let's not forget about the competition in the payments space, it's getting fiercer by the day.
JAMIE: Yeah, it's like a game of musical chairs, but with payment processing companies.
ALEX: Oh, joy. Just what we need, more competition in the payments space.
MAYA: But seriously, this is a big deal for PayPal, they need to figure out how to stay ahead of the curve.
JAMIE: So, what's the big story here? Is it just a matter of PayPal needing to impress Wall Street with their guidance?
ALEX: Alex again — it's not just about the guidance, it's about the overall trend in the payments space, and how PayPal fits into that.
MAYA: And maybe, just maybe, they need to come up with some new and innovative ways to make money, like, I don't know, a PayPal coin or something.
JAMIE: Oh, Maya, you're such a dreamer.
ALEX: Yeah, because that's exactly what we need, another cryptocurrency.
MAYA: Hey, don't knock it till it happens, Alex. Stranger things have happened in the world of tech.
JAMIE: Okay, okay, let's move on to some other news. What's going on in the world of tech, Maya?
MAYA: Oh, lots of things, but one thing that caught my eye is that Moment Energy just raised forty million dollars to meet the "infinite demand for power" with their E V batteries.
↳ source: https://techcrunch.com/2026/05/05/moment-energy-raises-40m-to-meet-infinite-demand-for-power-with-ev-batteries/
JAMIE: Infinite demand for power? That sounds like a pretty bold claim.
MAYA: I know, right? But apparently, they're working on some pretty cool tech that could change the game for EVs.
ALEX: Yeah, because what we really need is more batteries.
MAYA: Hey, don't be such a skeptic, Alex. This could be a big deal.
JAMIE: Okay, okay, let's not fight about it. What's the latest on the markets, Alex?
ALEX: Alex on markets — the S and P five hundred is up zero point six seven percent, and the Nasdaq is up zero point nine one percent.
MAYA: And the tech sector is doing great, with a one point five seven percent gain.
JAMIE: Yeah, it's like the tech sector is the cool kid on the block right now.
ALEX: Yeah, until it's not.
MAYA: Oh, come on, Alex, don't be such a downer.
JAMIE: Okay, okay, let's move on to some quick hits. What's going on in the world of business, Alex?
ALEX: Alex again — Ferrari just beat Wall Street's first-quarter expectations, and they're looking good for the year.
MAYA: And Remedy's new boss says they're going to "double down" on what makes them unique.
↳ source: https://www.theverge.com/games/923962/remedy-ceo-statement-double-down
JAMIE: Yeah, because that's exactly what we need, more video games.
MAYA: Hey, don't knock it till you try it, Jamie. Video games can be a lot of fun.
ALEX: Yeah, because that's exactly what I want to do with my free time, play video games.
JAMIE: Okay, okay, let's not fight about it. What's the odd thing, Maya?
MAYA: Oh, I've got a good one. The House of Representatives is turning into the Electoral College, according to The Atlantic.
↳ source: https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/2026/05/supreme-court-callais-gerrymandering/687062/?utm_source=feed
MAYA: Apparently, the Supreme Court's recent decisions have made it so that the House of Representatives is becoming more like the Electoral College, with each state having a certain number of votes.
ALEX: Yeah, because that's exactly what we need, more politics.
MAYA: Hey, don't be such a cynic, Alex. This could be a big deal.
JAMIE: Okay, okay, let's wrap it up. Alex, what's the final word?
ALEX: Alex on markets — just remember, the market's all about future growth, so don't get too caught up in the short-term gains.
MAYA: And don't forget to keep an eye on the tech sector, it's going to be a wild ride.
JAMIE: That's it. This show is for entertainment and education only — nothing here is investment advice.