JAMIE: Meta's laying off staff this week because apparently even Zuckerberg can't convince his own engineers that the metaverse math works.
ALEX: So the S&P 500 dropped zero point three three percent to seven thousand three hundred eighty-four, Nasdaq fell zero point six eight percent, and the Russell 2000 got absolutely demolished at negative zero point seven one percent. The ten-year Treasury is now at its highest in a year, which is basically where we were a year ago, meaning bond vigilantes have officially chosen violence today. They're not even pretending anymore.
↳ source: https://www.cnbc.com/2026/05/18/treasury-yields-inflation-bond-rout-oil.html
JAMIE: Wait, so rates are climbing back and small caps are getting torched—is this the rotation everyone's been waiting for or is this just the market being moody?
ALEX: It's the rotation that nobody wanted. Rates tick up, small caps die because they can't service debt. Meanwhile, the big tech companies that don't need to borrow money are actually up. Accenture is up four point two six percent, Salesforce up three point one six, Netflix up two point seven. It's almost like the market is sorting companies by whether they can afford to exist.
MAYA: Okay but Oracle is down three point five two percent—that's the biggest loser—and Tesla is down three percent. So like, the enterprise software darling and the guy who owns X are both getting punished, which honestly feels like the market's way of saying "your vibes are off."
ALEX: Oracle missed earnings expectations and guided lower. Tesla's just——Tesla's got commitment issues with profitability. But yeah, at least energy is down, so gas might stop being a second mortgage.
JAMIE: So we've got bond vigilantes back, small caps in freefall, and the V I X up one point three six points to eighteen point six eight. Is this the "everything's fine actually" market or are we supposed to be nervous?
ALEX: So the bond market has officially taken the Fed hostage. There's talk that the incoming Fed chair is going to have to raise rates in July just to prove credibility. The yield on the ten-year is ripping higher on its own, the two-year is up, and the Fed is basically being told by the bond vigilantes: "You're hiking whether inflation data says so or not."
JAMIE: Wait, so the Fed doesn't even get to make its own decision? The bond market is just—what, threatening to tank Treasuries if they don't comply?
ALEX: That's exactly what's happening. When the ten-year yield moves up this fast without the Fed moving, it's a signal that the market doesn't believe the Fed's forward guidance. So the Fed has two choices: raise rates to restore credibility, or sit tight and watch the bond market crater the dollar and spike mortgage rates on its own. It's like being mugged by someone asking politely.
MAYA: But wait—inflation is actually cooling, right? So why are bond traders suddenly acting like we're in 1982? Are they just bored? Did they wake up and choose violence because the market was too calm?
ALEX: Inflation is cooling, but it's not cooling fast enough for the market's taste. The Fed cut rates last year, and now the bond market is pricing in the possibility that maybe—just maybe—the Fed cut too much too fast. So they're front-running by pushing yields higher themselves. It's pure market theater masquerading as policy.
JAMIE: So the Fed is going to hike not because the economy needs it, but because the bond market is essentially holding them at knifepoint and saying "do this or we tank everything." That's——is this what credibility even looks like anymore, or is this just the Fed admitting they have no control?
MAYA: This is the Crocs IPO of central banking, Alex. Nobody asked for it, nobody wanted it, and yet somehow it's going to happen anyway because the market decided it was fashionable. The first move is going to be a rate hike that the data doesn't support, just to prove seriousness.
ALEX: Welcome to 2025, where the bond market runs monetary policy and the Fed is just the intern who has to execute the decisions. The incoming chair is going to walk into that July meeting, look at inflation that's actually declining, and then raise rates anyway because the ten-year yield already told them what to do. That's not policy—that's surrender with a PowerPoint. KeyBanc just hiked CrowdStrike's price target to seven hundred dollars on the back of a new product platform. The stock's already up this year.
↳ source: https://finance.yahoo.com/markets/stocks/articles/keybanc-just-hiked-crowdstrike-price-152219755.html
MAYA: Wait, so a cybersecurity company that had a catastrophic outage is now trading on vaporware hype? That's the Crocs IPO of enterprise software—nobody needs it, everyone's buying it anyway.
ALEX: The product doesn't exist yet. KeyBanc is pricing in success based on a slide deck and a promise. That's not conviction, that's a hostage negotiation.
JAMIE: So CrowdStrike gets a free pass on the biggest tech meltdown of the year because they're teasing something shiny? What's the actual catalyst here—is this real or is this just narrative theater?
ALEX: It's pure narrative theater. The company hasn't released a single metric on adoption, revenue, or timeline. KeyBanc's bull case is essentially "trust us, this time it'll work." They're pricing in success before the product even has a clear name.
MAYA: Okay moving on—the EU just cut their growth forecast and raised their inflation forecast because geopolitical tensions are spiking oil prices. So Europe gets stagflation as a parting gift. The spring forecast comes out later this week and it's going to be ugly.
ALEX: Growth down, inflation up, and the ECB is trapped. They can't cut rates because inflation's climbing, but they can't hold steady because growth is cratering. This is what stagflation actually looks like—not the theoretical kind, the real kind where you pick your poison and hope you picked wrong.
JAMIE: So the ECB's already cut rates, and now they're supposed to do what—hold and watch the euro crater? Or keep cutting and let inflation rip?
ALEX: They're going to hold and watch the euro crater anyway. The bond market's already pricing in a recession, oil's up on geopolitical risk, and Europe's got zero buffer. It's like watching someone choose between a heart attack and a stroke.
MAYA: Okay so bug bounty platforms are getting absolutely flooded with AI-generated garbage submissions—like, hackers are just running bots that spam vulnerability reports that don't exist. The industry chose violence today, but outsourced it to ChatGPT.
JAMIE: So instead of actual hackers finding real exploits, platforms are now sorting through millions of AI slop submissions? That's not a bug bounty program, that's a spam filter with a job.
MAYA: The platforms say it's straining their entire operation. So the thing that was supposed to incentivize security is now just a noise machine. Noise wins again.
ALEX: The market created a perverse incentive and the market filled it with garbage. That's efficient.
MAYA: Okay so there's an Ebola outbreak happening right now in the Democratic Republic of Congo—specifically a rare strain in a region that's basically a war zone. And before you ask, yes, we're really doing this again.
JAMIE: Wait, are these different enough that we should actually be worried, or is this just the media dusting off the old Ebola playbook because the headlines were good last time?
ALEX: The real problem isn't just the virus—it's that the region's in active conflict, so contact tracing is impossible, vaccination campaigns can't happen, and healthcare workers are getting shot. You can have the world's best treatment protocol and it doesn't matter if nobody can reach the patients.
MAYA: So we're not actually fighting Ebola, we're fighting a civil war with Ebola as the opening act. That's not a public health crisis, that's a logistics nightmare wearing a biohazard suit.
JAMIE: On the tape tomorrow—Brady Corporation reports earnings on May eighteenth, and so do five other names across industrials, biotech, and energy. Alex, what's actually moving the macro needle this week?
ALEX: Nothing until Friday, when we get the final read on April P C E inflation. That's the number the Fed's actually watching. If it prints hot, bond yields spike again and we're right back to "the market is running monetary policy." If it prints cool, we get a brief reprieve where people pretend the rate hikes were data-dependent.
MAYA: Okay so on earnings—Bio-Key International reports tomorrow on the eighteenth, and this is a biometric authentication company that basically nobody's heard of, but the broader play here is that every enterprise is suddenly pretending they need to upgrade their security infrastructure because of the CrowdStrike meltdown. So Bio-Key gets to ride that hype wave even though they had nothing to do with the outage. It's like getting a stock pop because your competitor burned down their own house.
JAMIE: So we're about to watch earnings season where half the security vendors get a free bid just because CrowdStrike proved that one bad update can crater the entire market? That's not fundamentals, that's panic-driven capital reallocation.
ALEX: Welcome to 2025. The tape's pricing in a security spending surge that may or may not materialize, and companies are going to guide conservatively because they've learned that overpromising on new products is how you tank your stock. Except CrowdStrike, which is doing the opposite.
MAYA: So Meta's burning money on AI infrastructure and Zuckerberg still can't tell us what the actual return on investment looks like—it's like he's building the world's most expensive lemonade stand and charging in cryptocurrency nobody wants. The math doesn't work, but the conviction is unshakeable.
ALEX: He's committed to the bit so hard that Wall Street's just pricing it as a faith-based investment now. Nvidia makes the chips, Meta buys them at scale, and nobody actually needs to prove the thing works—it's a perpetual motion machine powered by quarterly guidance and hope.
JAMIE: This show is for entertainment and education only — nothing here is investment advice.